Guide to the Beatrice Straight papers, [ca. 1925]-1990.
Straight, Beatrice papers, [ca. 1925]-1990
- Series III. Professional Papers
  - Publicity materials [(B)=Beatrice participated, (P)=Peter Cookson participated
    - "A Streetcar Named Desire": press releases, clippings, programs, reviews (B), 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - "A Streetcar Named Desire": clippings album (B), 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "A Sunday With Beatrice Straight": invitation, program (B), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - "The Tennis Game": clipping (B. helped get started, did not act in this production), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - "This Wooden O": clipping (B), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - "Timbuktu!": clippings (B), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - "Tobacco Road": program, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - "Tom Stoppard's Dogg's Hamlet, Cahoot's MacBeth": programs, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - "Trial of Poznan": clipping (P), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - "Twelfth Night": clipping (B), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - "The Underground Reporter": clipping (B), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - "Waltz of the Toreadors": reviews (B), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - "Who Am I?": program, clippings (production of Young World Foundation [one of B.'s projects]), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - "Who Am I?": broadsides, [1972] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "The Winter's Tale": program, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - "Wonder Woman": clippings (B), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - "The World of Darkness": clipping (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Scripts [(B) indicates performance/production in which B. Straight took part)]
    - "An Act of Love," by Willis Cooke (Peter W. Cookson), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - "The Actor," by Peter Cookson, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - "An Actor's Dream," by Peter Cookson, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - "The American," dramatized by Ellen Van Volkenburg from the romance by Henry James (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - "Ay and What Then?" P. W. Ceigh (Peter W. Cookson), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - "Bedroom Farce," Gary Anthony (Peter W. Cookson), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - "Bedroom Farce," Gary Anthony (Peter W. Cookson), 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "A Bit of Fluff," Peter Cookson, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "The Borrowers": clippings, scripts (B), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - "Both Our Houses," Peter Cookson, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Contradictions," P. W. Ceigh, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Coo," Peter Cookson, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Dr. D & the 10 Speed Bicycle," Peter Cookson, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Eastward in Eden: The Love Story of Emily Dickinson," by Dorothy Gardner (B), n. d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Epic That Never Was" (B), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Expecting Max" Peter Cookson, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "A Fair Exchange" Peter Cookson, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "For Love or Money" Peter Cookson, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Frozen Man," J. D. Feigelson (B), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Ghosts", [1973] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "The Glass Menagerie," Tennessee Williams (B), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Grace at Table Six," Peter Cookson, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "The Hallucinations of Paul Tremaine," Peter Cookson, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "Henderson's Head," by Peter Cookson (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Ibsen's Life and Times" (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "The Magic Pilot", 1944 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Mania!" P. W. Cookson, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Maniac!" P. W. Cookson, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Memories of Midnight," Sidney Shelton (B), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "The Palace at 4 A. M." Howard Moss (B), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Palomino," Danielle Steele (B), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Phèdre," by Jean Racine (B), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Pigeons," Peter Cookson, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Poltergeist," Steven Spielberg (B), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "The Right honourable Gentleman," M. Bradley-Dyne (prompt script) (B), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "The Right Honourable Gentleman" (revised version) (B), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Robert Kennedy and His Times" (B), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "Second Chance" (B), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Stanley," Gary Anthony (Peter W. Cookson) [2 versions] (B), [1970] (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "A Streetcar Named Desire," Tennessee Williams (2 acting editions) (B), [1967-1970] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Tell Me Later," Peter Cookson, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Three Million Rosebuds," Peter Cookson (1st draft), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Three Million Rosebuds," Peter Cookson (completed copy), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Two Acts of Murder," Willis Cooke (Peter Cookson), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Two Acts of Murder" (second copy), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "Unique Species," Peter Cookson, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Used people," Todd Graff (B), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Where Evil Dwells," Robert A. Suhosky and Peter W. Cookson (second revised rewrite), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Where Evil Dwells," R. A. S. and P. W. C. (third revised rewrite), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "Who's Who in Connecticut," P. W. Cookson, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Proposals
    - "The Bride, the Swans and the Mountain Lion," Michael Straight (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "Once Upon a Castle," Beatrice Straight and Brian Froud (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "The Saving Circle," Ingo Swann, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Awards/Honors
  - Academy Awards, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - American Biographical Institute, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - American Biographical Institute (small medal), n. d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - American Biographical Institute (large medal), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Distinguished Women of Northwood Institute", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The John Fitzgerald Kennedy Library medal, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Screen Actors Guild, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - "Stars of the New York Stage, 1870-1970" (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Tony Awards (1977 clipping), 1953 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - U. S. Presidential inauguration invitation, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Who's Who in the East", 1983/1984 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Who's Who in the East", 1986/1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Who's Who in the East", 1991/1992 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Who's Who in the Theatre" (bound volume), 1952 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "Who's Who in the World", 1984/1985 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "Who's Who of American women", 1977/1978 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "Who's Who of American women", 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "Who's Who of American women", 1981/1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "Who's Who of American women", 1983/1984 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Series V. Business Materials
  - Business miscellany
    - Contracts/Agreements, 1971-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Receipts/Invoices, 1973, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Business Miscellaneous, 1973, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Personal miscellany
    - Beatrice Cruise: performance of "Deadly Voyage", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Beatrice Miscellaneous: astrological chart, horoscope, miscellany, 1978-1989, n. d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Peter Cookson materials
    - "And Never Asking Why," Peter Cookson ("words for music"), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Book," Peter Cookson: draft (Box 9, Folder 10-14)
    - "Henderson's Head," Peter Cookson: miscellaneous correspondence and material, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Henderson's Head": uncorrected proofs (2), 1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Peter Cookson on Berkshire Theatre Fund (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Peter Cookson reminiscences, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series VI. Visual Images
  - Photographs
    - Beatrice in India (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Beatrice: portraits, n. d., 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "All My Sons" (B), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lewis Allen, Beatrice, ?, [1975?] (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Alley Theatre event, Houston, Texas (B), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Andros Targets": Beatrice, Richard Kiley (B), 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Barretts of Wimpole Street" (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Barretts of Wimpole Street" (B), n. d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Beacon Hill" (B), [1975-1978] (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Book of Hours" (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Michael Chekhov, 1940, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Chekhov Group; Ridgefield, Connecticut, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Chekhov Studio, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Beatrice and Peter Cookson (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Peter Cookson and Arlene Francis, Wendy Hiller, and Gail Storm, 1945, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Dartington Hall and Chekhov Theatre (B) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Dartington Hall campus, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Deadly Voyage, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Eastward in Eden" with Onslow Stevens, Beatrice Marley, Edwin Perone (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Mother (Dorothy W. S. Elmhirst), Deidre, Mishe (Michael Chekhov), Xzania at Dartington, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "Ghosts" (B), [1973] (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "The Glass Menagerie" (B), [1980] (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Globe Theatre tour in England with Sam Wanamaker (B) (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Hamlet" (B), [1979] (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "Heartbreak House," by G. B. Shaw with Larry Gates, Mary Lou Taylor, Peter Cookson (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "Heartbreak House" with Larry Gates (B), n. d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "The Heiress" with Wendy Hiller, Peter Cookson, Basil Rathbone (B) (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "The Heiress" with Basil Rathbone (B), n. d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "The Innocents" with Iris Mann, David Cole, Isabel Elson (B), [1950] (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - The Innocents" (B), [1950] (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "King Lear" with Yul Bryner, Hurd Hatfield, Ford Rainy, Mary Lou Taylor, John Flynn, Grael Regan (B), [1953] (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "Kings Crossing" with Bradford Dillman, Mary Frann, Linda Hamilton, Dorothy Meyer, Marilyn Jones, Daniel Zippi, Doreen Clark (B), [1981-1982] (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - "Land of Fame" with Albert Bell, Norman Rose (B) (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "Long Way Home" with James Daly, Frances Heflin (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "MacBeth" with Michael Redgrave (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "Network" with William Holden (B), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Network" Academy Award photos with Sylvester Stallone, Muhammed Ali, Sidney Lumet (B), 1977 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - N. Y. S. Department of Agriculture presentation to Mayor Koch (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Night of 100 Stars (2 photographs), 1982 (Map-case Folder 3)
    - "Nun's Story" with Audrey Hepburn, Colleen Dewhurst (B), [1951] (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "Old Times" with Raúl Julia and Irene Worth (B), [1977] (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - "Old Times" with Raúl Julia and Irene Worth (B), [1977] (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Old Vic stars with Gertrude Lawrence, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "Patterns" with Van Heflin (B), [1955-]1956 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Gregory Peck on the beach, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Phèdre" (B), 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - "Phèdre (B), [1965-1966] (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Phoenix production, N. Y. C. (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - "Phone call from a Stranger" with James Mason, Eli Wallach(?), Wendy Hiller (B) (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "Playboy of the Western World" with Gregory Peck (B), 1946 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - "Poltergeist" (B), 1982 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - "The Possessed" with John Flynn, Woodrow Chambliss (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Tony Randall, Eli Wallach, Beatrice (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - "The Right Honourable Gentleman" with Henderson Forsythe, Sarah Badel, Marie Wallace, Francis Bethencourt; Edward Mulhare, Carolyn Lagerfelt (B), [1971] (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - "Robert Kennedy and His Times" (B), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Edward G. Robinson (B), n. d. (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - "Second Chance" with John Travolta (B), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Uday Shankar, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - "Silken Affair" with David Niven, Geraldine Page, [Terry Thomas] (B), [1956] (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Skowhegan Dinner with Gerda Vanderbilt, Beatrice, Michael Valenti (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - "Streetcar Named Desire" (B), [1967-1970] (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - "Two of a Kind" with Charles Durning, Oliver Reed (B) (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Beatrice and Michael Valenti (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Theatreworks/USA (B), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - "Who Am I?" (B), [1972] (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Beatrice: portrait, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified roles (B)/set, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Beatrice unidentified role, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Family and friends: Dorothy [W. S. E.], Flora, Willard Straight, Beatrice, unidentified (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Two interiors: "picture from bedroom front/east wall, n. d. (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Drawings
    - Sketches: costumes, n. d. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Sketches: horses, artist unidentified, n. d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Dartington Hall theatre plans, n. d. (Map-case Folder 1)
    - Sketches: "Right Honourable Gentleman", n. d. (Map-case Folder 2)
    - Two chalk drawings [Hans Schaukar(sp?)], [1929] (Map-case Folder 3)
    - Sketch: Beatrice Straight Cookson, n. d. (Map-case Folder 4)
    - Sketch: unidentified man [Michael Chekhov?], 1929 (Map-case Folder 4)
    - Sketch: set at Dartington Hall theatre, n. d. (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Films
    - "Nevada 1949", F-1055
    - "The Garden Party", n. d.; F-1056 (Box 13)
    - "Bali Reel 1 Dup", n. d.; F-1057 (Box 13)
    - Greece?: very few shots of Bea - mostly landscape, F-1058 (Box 13)
    - Bea's trip to Russia (she is not seen on film), n. d.; F-1059 (Box 13)
    - Children at the Chalet, n. d.; F-1060 (Box 13)
    - 2 films, unclear which is which:, n. d.; F-1061-1062 (Box 13)
      -India - to be spliced
      -Uday Shankar (to be spliced)
    - India: Bea, Deidre Duprey, very little of Bea - landscape, F-1063 (Box 13)
    - 4 films, unclear which is which:, n. d.; F-1064-1067 (Box 13)
      -Children at Dartington Hall
      -England, Chalet, Dartington Hall
      -Not identified [travel: U. S. or India possibly Old Parsonage Farm]
      -[Travel:] Malabar, Cochin fisherman, Bombay, Udaipur (No. 2)
    - Eloise, n. d.; F-1068 (Box 13)
    - No identification, n. d.; F-1069 (Box 13)
    - Not identified, n. d.; F-1070 (Box 13)
    - ↓ 3 films below deteriorating ↓
    - [Travel: India:] Fate pur, Sikri, Ellora, Ajanta, Almora (No. 4), F-1052 (Box 14)
    - Uday Shankar - original and duplicates, 1934; F-1053 (Box 14)
    - [Travel:] Gibraltar, Cairo, Board Ship, Cawn Anir, n. d.; F-1054 (Box 14)
- Series VII. Sound Recordings
  - Audio tapes
    - Accompaniments: 260 End of Caro Meo Ben, 265 Begin Ney Ver De Sehn, 2/35 Amarillo (Box 12)
    - Beatrice Straight, n. d. (Box 12)
    - Lady MacBeth "Sleepwalking Scene", n. d. (Box 12)
    - No Dialogue, need slate, n. d. (Box 12)
    - "Right Honourable Gentleman" tape B, [1971] (Box 12)
    - "Stanley" (2 reels), n. d. (Box 12)
    - "Who Am I?", n. d. (Box 12)
    - Not identified, n. d. (Box 12)
    - Amor Ti Vieta, 1955 (Box 12)
    - Barry Heard, n. d. (Box 12)
  - 78's
    - Music from "The Promise" (B), 1979; SR-1
    - Peter Cookson, London, "demo", 1955; SR-2
    - Peter Cookson, 1955; SR-3-6
- Series VIII. Personal Materials
  - Appointment books
    - Spiral notebooks and date books (15), 1971-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1-15)
  - Miscellaneous personal
    - Certificate from flight on Concorde, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sketches: costuming ideas, n. d. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - 2 wicker suitcases, MU-1086, MU-1087